<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Do Hoang</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Do Hoang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Do Hoang. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 17:59:52 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Xf86 Video Intel</title>
      <link>/posts/xf86-video-intel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 17:59:52 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/xf86-video-intel/</guid>
      <description>Why not XF86-Video-Intel ? It is a DDX driver (which provides 2D acceleration in Xorg) but It is not recommended to install nowaday. Because this package is no longer needed and also causes screen tearing. And also the generic xf86-video-modesetting DDX driver included in xorg-server seems to be better than most vendor specific xf86-video- drivers.
Some (Debian &amp;amp; Ubuntu, Fedora, KDE) recommend not installing the xf86-video-intel driver, and instead falling back on the modesetting driver for Gen4 and newer GPUs (GMA 3000 from 2006 and newer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick terminal-based DNS switching</title>
      <link>/posts/dns-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 21:39:45 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dns-command/</guid>
      <description>This post was originally published on thecodecousins by StanleyNguyen. I add the Linux section for more details.
Motivation Most of us, at some point of our lives, have used at least a custom DNS servers configurations for our computers. Be it for avoiding censorship, faster browsing, security, or bypassing content restriction, we&amp;rsquo;ve all tried setting our DNS servers to some public DNS servers like one from Google (remember 8.8.8.8 and 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I made the switch from Mac to Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/dellxps-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 19:45:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dellxps-arch/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been a huge Mac fan and power user since I started in IT in 2015. But a few months ago—for several reasons — I made the commitment to shift to Linux as my daily driver. This isn&amp;rsquo;t my first attempt at fully adopting Linux, but I&amp;rsquo;m finding it easier than ever. Here is what inspired me to switch.
Why Im falling in love with macOS First of all, in 2015 I had my very first macOS laptop which is an Macbook air 13 inch model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcode to Insert Raw HTML in Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/shortcode-to-insert-raw-html-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 23:31:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/shortcode-to-insert-raw-html-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is very good framework of creating a website by using markdown. But there are times when Markdown falls short. Often, content authors are forced to add raw HTML (e.g., video &amp;lt;iframes&amp;gt;) to Markdown content.
But Hugo does not seem to have a good way to let you do this in a markdown file. They created shortcodes to circumvent these limitations.
A shortcode is a simple snippet inside a content file that Hugo will render using a predefined template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Arduino With PharoThings/Smalltalk</title>
      <link>/posts/using-arduino-with-pharo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 19:57:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/using-arduino-with-pharo/</guid>
      <description>Firmata Firmata is a generic protocol for communicating with microcontrollers from software on a host computer. It is intended to work with any host computer software package. Right now there is a matching object in a number of languages. It is easy to add objects for other software to use this protocol. Basically, this firmware establishes a protocol for talking to the Arduino from the host software. The aim is to allow people to completely control the Arduino from software on the host computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Revert to a Good Commit</title>
      <link>/posts/git-revert-to-a-good-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 14:28:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/git-revert-to-a-good-commit/</guid>
      <description>Today my co-worker asked me how to revert to an old and good commit on master ( after you accidentally merged dev branch to master ). There are many ways to do that, for example we can use reset to discard all wrong commit to revert back, like undo when writing text. You can find others way onthis topic on Stack Overflow But the problem is too many options, we dont know which one is good, or even dont need to understand - it just works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I escaped from Microsoft Office tools as a Computer Science student</title>
      <link>/posts/pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:35:20 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pandoc/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I have used beamer quite a lot to prepare slides for both research and class presentations. I have started to use LaTeX to content in beamer presentation for two years. Sometimes I was concerned about the high ratio of markup to content in beamer presentations. I used to type thousands lines of code just to create a presentation slide which was tiring and time consuming. Thus, I did some research and found a combination of pandoc, markdown, and LaTeX to simplify my process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Hello, friend?&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s lame.
Maybe I should give you a name&amp;hellip;
But that&amp;rsquo;s a slippery slope.
You&amp;rsquo;re only in my head.
We have to remember that&amp;hellip;
Shit.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually happened.
I&amp;rsquo;m talking to an imaginary person.
— Mr. Robot S01E01
 #about An inquisitive explorer of both the digital and physical worlds.
I am blessed to receive my education from:
 University of Science and Technology of Hanoi (USTH)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showcase</title>
      <link>/showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/showcase/</guid>
      <description>University of Science and Technology 3D virtual world game </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>